Guide to the Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
- B
  - ________. "Multiple fractures of the pelvis with rupture of he bladder." Reprinted from Transactions of the American Association of Genito-Urinary Surgeons, 1927. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Postoperative care of urological cases." Reprinted from The American journal of surgery, July 1931. (Box 1)
  - ________. and Arthur J. Murphy. "The value and limitations of uroselectan as an aid in urological diagnosis." Reprinted from The Journal of Urology, March 1931. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Silent ureteral calculi." Reprinted from the Transactions of the American Association of Genito-Urinary Surgeons for 1930. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Cases of unsuspected carcinom of the prostate discovered on microscopic section." Reprinted from The Journal of urology, October 1929. (Box 1)
  - Bullard, Margerite J. "Study of the Bacterial Flora of the Intestinal Mucusa of the Normal Rabbit." American Medicine, 4 October 1902. (Box 1)
  - Bunting, C.H. "The Effects of lymphotoxins and myelotoxins on the leucocytes of the blood and on the blood-forming organs." Reprinted from the University of Pennsylvania Medical Bulletin, July-August 1903 (Box 1)
  - Burnett, Samuel H. "The clinical examination of the blood of the dog." Reprinted from 42nd Annual Proceedings of A.V.M.A., 1905 (Box 1)
  - ________. "The control of an outbreak of anthrax." Reprinted from American Veterinary Review, May 1908. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Notes on the clinical examination of the blood of the domesticated animals." American Veterinary Review, December 1903. (Box 1)
  - Busch, F.C. and A.T. Kerr, Jr. "The relation between the specific gravity of the blood and its hemoglobin-percentage." Reprinted from The Medical News, December 1895. (Box 1)
  - Busch, F.C., A.T. Kerr, Jr., and F. Filsinger "The relation of the specific gravity of the blood to its percentage of hemoglobin." Reprinted from Buffalo Medical Journal, October, 1900. (Box 1)
  - Busey, Samuel C. "The duties of physicians to the profession and their relation to the medical charities of the district of Columbia." Reprinted from Transactions of the medical society of the District of Columbia, 15 December 1897. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Compulsory Reports of Zygotic Diseases; Milk Legislation; Medical Practice Law; And Society Publication of its Transactions." Annual Address of the President of the Medical Society of the District of Columbia, 18 December 1895. (Box 1)
  - Buxton, R.H. "Bacterial Purification of Sewage." Reprinted from The Philadelphia Medical Journal, 5 April 1902. (Box 1)
- C
  - Calhoun, M. Lois. "The Microscopic Anatomy of the Digestive Tract of gallus domesticus." Reprinted from Iowa State College Journal of Science, 1933/ (Box 1)
  - Calvin, Joseph K. and A.H. Goldberg. "Plasma Proteins and Edema: Their relationship in a group of children presenting the nephritic syndrome" Reprinted from the American Journal of Diseases of Children, August 1931. (Box 1)
  - Cameron, A.T. and D. Nicholson. "An improved mode of expression of haemoglobin values." Reprinted from The Canadian Medical Association Journal, XVI, 1926. (Box 1)
  - Cameron, Hugh Stuart. "The viability of brucella abortus." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, Vol. XXII, No.3, July 1932. (Box 1)
  - Campbell, H.C. "Leucocytes in Milk: Methods of Determination and the effect of heat upon their number." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin 117, 1909. (Box 1)
  - Campell, S.B. Boyd and S.I. Turkington. "Right bundle-branch blook. An analysis of the clinical records of fifty-six cases with typical electrocardiograms" Reprinted from Quarterly Journal of Medicine, July 1931. (Box 1)
  - Canadian Department of Agriculture. "Hog Cholera." Department of Agriculture, Health of Animals Branch Bulletin, No 15, July 1915. (Box 1)
  - Cannon, Walter B. "The dog's gift to the relief of human suffering." Reprinted from Hygenia, January 1926. (Box 1)
  - Caramanis, Jean C. "Contribution à l'étude de quelques modifications fonctionelles de la cellule nerveuse." University of Geneva Thesis, 1919. (Box 1)
  - Carlson, Anton J. and Frederick Hoelzel. "Apparent prolongation of the life span of rats by intermittent fasting." Reprinted from the Journal of Nutrition, March 1946. (Box 1)
  - Caroli, Jacques and Marcel Bessis. "Médecine - Sur la cause et le traitement de l'ictère grave des Muletons nouveau-nés." Reprinted from Comptes Rendus des Séances de l'Académie des Sciences, March 1947. (Box 1)
  - Carpenter, Charles M. "Brucella abortus in udders of vaccinated and naturally infected cattle." Cornell Veterinarian, April 1926. (Box 1)
  - _______. "A study of milk from cows showing no agglutins for brucella abortus in their blood serum." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1927. (Box 1)
  - Carter, Edward P. and Benjamin Baker Jr. "Certain aspects of syphilitic cardiac disease." Reprinted from Bulletin of John Hopkins Hospital, May 1931. (Box 1)
  - Carter, H. R. "Methods of the conveyance of yellow fever infection." United States Treasury Department, Bureau of Public Health and Marine-Hospital Service, Yellow Fever Institute Bulletin No. 10, 1902. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Shipment of merchandise from a town infected with yellow fever." United States Treasury Department, Marine-Hospital Service, 1899 (Box 1)
  - _______. "Train inspection in yellow fever epidemics." Reprinted from Annual Report Marine-Hospital Service, United States Treasury Department, 1899. (Box 1)
  - Carter, William S. "The globulicidal action of blood-serum." Reprinted from University Medical Magazine, December 1893. (Box 1)
  - Carter, William Wesley. "The importance of nasal plastic surgery." Reprinted from The Larynogoscope, July 1930. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Transposition of Section from the Auricle for the Correction of a Nasal Defect." Reprinted from the Archives of Otolaryngology, August 1930. (Box 1)
  - Cary. C.A. "Bovine tuberculosis." Alabama Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 67, November 1895. (Box 1)
  - Cattell, J. McKeen. "Some psychological experiments." Reprinted from Science, 1 January and 8 January 1926. (Box 1)
  - Celi. A and R. Fiocca. "Beitrage zur Amobenforshung. Zweite vorlaufige Mitteilung. Ueber die Klassifikation der Amoben und einige gezuchtete Species." Pasoerorean, May 1894. (Box 1)
  - Central New York Fur Company. "Silver black fox farming and its opportunities." 1922. (Box 1)
  - Chapin, Charles V. "Some Sanitary Problems." The annual address before the Rhode Island Medical Society, 26 May 1908. (Box 1)
  - Chester, F.D. "Protective inoculation against anthrax." The Proceedings of the Seventeenth meeting of the Society for the Promotion of Agriculutural Sciences, August 1896. (Box 1)
  - Chown, Bruce, Marion Lewis and Anna Bryce. "On the detection, differentiation and titration of anti-Rh antibodies." Reprinted from the Canadian Medical Association Journal, 1948. (Box 1)
  - Chown, Bruce and Marion Lewis. "Further experience with the slanted capillary method for rh typing of red blood cells." Reprinted from The Canadian Medical Association Journal, 1946. (Box 1)
  - Church, H.R., M.F. Barnes, W.H. Ridge and F.A. Marshall. "Infectious abortion and sterility" Bulletin of the Pennsylvania Department of Agriculture, December 1921. (Box 1)
  - Claypole, Agnes Mary. "The enterion of the Cayuga Lake lamprey." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the American Microscopical Society, 1894. (Box 1)
  - ________. "New method for securing paraffin sections to the slide or cover-glass." Proceedings of the American Microscopial Society, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Claypole, Edith J. "An Investigation of the blood of necturus and cryptobranchus." Extract from Proceedings, 1893. (Box 1)
  - Clift, A.F. "Observations on certain rheological properties of human cervical secretion." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Royal Society of Medicine, November 1945. (Box 1)
  - Coit, Henry L. "The work of medical milk commissions in the campaign for the betterment of milk production and distribution." Reprinted from Transactions of the Fifteenth International Congress on Hygiene and Demography, 23-28 September 1912. (Box 1)
  - Cole, Leon J., et al. "Blackhead in turkeys: A study in avian coccidiosis."Agricultural Experiment Station of the Rhode Island State College bulletin, No 141, June 1910. (Box 1)
  - Connaway, J.W. "Hog cholera and immature corn." University of Missouri College of Agriculture, Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 174, September 1920. (Box 1)
  - Coombs, R.R.A.; R.C. Crowhurst, F.T. Day, D.H. Heard, I.T. Hinde, J. Hoogstraten and H.B. Parry. "Haemolytic disease of newborn foals due to iso-immunization of pregnancy." Reprinted from The Journal of Hygiene, December 1948. (Box 1)
  - Cope, C.L. "the excretion of creatinine by the human kidney in health and in nephritis." Quarterly Journal of Medicine, July 1931. (Box 1)
  - Cope, E.D. "On the characters of some Paleozoic fishes." Proceedings of the United States National Museum, 1891. (Box 1)
  - Councilman, W.T., F.B. Mallory and R.M. Pearce. "Diphtheria: a study of the bacteriology and pathology of two hundred and twenty fatal cases." 1901. (Box 1)
  - Crane, Douglas B. "Rotenone - a new parasiticide." Reprinted from Cornell Veterinarian, Vol. XXIII, No.1, January 1933. (Box 1)
  - Crawley, Howard. "Studies on blood and blood parasites." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 119, 1909. (Box 1)
  - Crosson, J. William et al. "Caronamide for increasing penicillin plasma concentrations in man." Reprinted from the Journal of the American Medical Association., 30 August 1947. (Box 1)
  - Curtice, Cooper. "The cattle tick." Reprinted form the Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, July 1891. (Box 1)
  - ________. "The oxwarble of the United States." Reprinted from the Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, June 1891. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Fowl typhoid." Rhode Island College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts, Bulletin No. 87 September1902. (Box 1)
- D
  - Dahlberg, A.C. "Increased milk production by improved machine milking." Cornell Extension Bulletin 606, War Emergency Bulletin 107, April 1943. (Box 1)
  - _______, George E. Holm and H.C. Troy. "A comparison of the babcock, gerber, and roesegottlieb method for determining the percentage of fat in milk and cream." New York State Agricultural Experiment Station bulletin, no 122, November 1926. (Box 1)
  - Dairymen's League. "The relation and importance of the ew York City milk market to the veterinarian." 1927. (Box 1)
  - Davies, Daniel T. "Studies on achlorhydria and anaemia." Reprinted from the Quarterly Journal of Medicine, July 1931. (Box 1)
  - Dawson Charles F. "Epithelioma contagiosum." Florida Agricultural experiment station department of veterinary science, 1 October 1902. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Hog cholera and swine plague." Florida Agricultural experiment station department of veterinary science, 15 March 1902. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Lumpy Jaw." Florida Agricultural experiment station department of veterinary science, 15 June 1902. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Moon Blindness." Florida Agricultural Experiment Station, Department of Veterinary Science, Bulletin No. 28, 15 July 1902. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Parturient paralysis." Florida Agricultural Experiment Station, Department of Veterinary Science, 15 April 1902. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Roup." Florida Agricultural Experiment Station, Department of Veterinary Science, 1 June 1902. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Some Poultry Pests." Florida Agricultural Experiment Station, Department of Veterinary Science,, 1 January and 15 January 1902. (Box 1)
  - Day, L. Enos. "Embryonal adenosacromoa of the kidney in swine." Reprinted from the Twenty-Fourth Annual Report of the Bureau of Animal Industry, 1907. (Box 1)
  - Dearborn, Ned. "Rabbit Growing to Supplement the Meat Supply." Separate from Yearbook of the Department of Agriculture, 1918, No. 784. (Box 1)
  - De Forest, Henry P. "Blindess of the newborn." Reprinted from the New York Medical Journal, 29 May and 5 June 1915. (Box 1)
  - _________. "Prostitution personal observations of police methods of dealing with prostituion in Germany." Reprinted form the New York State Journal of Medicine, October 1908. (Box 1)
  - De Jesus, Zacarias. "The Germicidal Properties of the Mixture of Kerosene and Coconut Oil." Philippine Agriculturist, February 1928. (Box 1)
  - De Schweinitz, E. A. "The War with the Microbes." Reprinted from Science, 9 April 1897. (Box 1)
  - _________, Marion Dorset and E.C. Schroeder. "Experiments concerning tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin, No. 52 pt. 2, 1905. (Box 1)
  - Deubler, Mary Josephine. "The anatomy and histology of the horse's eye." University of Pennsylvania dissertation, 1947. (Box 1)
  - Dexter, Franklin. "The development of the paraphysis in the common fowl." Reprinted from the American Journal of Anatomy, November 1902. (Box 1)
  - D'Herelle, F. "Annual Graduate Fortnight: bacteriohage as a treatment in acute medical and surgical infections." Bulletin of the New York Academy of Medicine, May 1931. (Box 1)
  - Dickinson, Robert Latou and Woodbridge Edwards Morris. "Techniques of Conception Control." A Practical Manual issues by the Birth Control Federation of America, 1941. (Box 1)
  - Dikmans, G. "Two new lungworms form North America ruminants and a note on the lungworms of sheep in the United States." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States National Musuem, 1931. (Box 1)
  - Dixon, Samuel G. "Koch's method of treating tuberculosis." Medical News, 17 January 1891. (Box 1)
  - _________. "Law, Foundatoin of state medicine." Reprinted from the Journal of American Medical Associations, 8 June 1907. (Box 1)
  - Doan, Charles A. "The clinical implications of experimental hematology." Reprinted from Medicine, September 1931. (Box 1)
  - Dobson, Aileen M. and Elizabeth W. Ikin. "The ABO blood groups in the United Kingdom; frequencies based on a very large sample." Reprinted from The Journal of Pathology and Bacteriology, 1946. (Box 1)
  - Dodson, W.R. "Nineteenth annual report of the agricultural experiment stations of the Louisiana State University and A. and M. College for 1906." (Box 1)
  - Dorset, Marion. "Experiments concerning tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 52 pt.1, 1904. (Box 1)
  - _________, C.N. McBryde and W. B. Niles." Further experiment concerning the production of immunity from hog cholera." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 102, 1908. (Box 1)
  - Douglass, Stephan A. and William C. Jensen. "Experience in finding tuberculosis cases in Cattaraugus county." Cattaraugus County Health Demonstration, 1 September 1926. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Sanatorium-home treatment aids tuberculosis fight." Reprinted from The Nation's Health, March 1962. (Box 1)
  - Dugger, J.F. and W.F. Ward. "Experiments in beef production in Alabama." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 103, 27 Feb 1908. (Box 1)
- E
  - Eager, J. M. "Yellow fever in France, Italy, Great Britain, and Austria, and Bibliography of Yellow Fever in Europe." United States Treasury Department, Marine-Hospital Service, Yellow Fever Institute Bulletin No. 8, May 1902. (Box 1)
  - Eber A. "Feststellung einheitlicher grundsatze fur die Beurteilung der Tuberkulinreaktion beim Rinde." VIII. Internationaler Tierarzlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905. (Box 1)
  - Eccles, R.G. "Darwinism and Diabetes." (Box 1)
  - Edland, Henrik. " To tilfeller av assimilasjon av atlas hos huspattedyr." Reprinted from Skandinavisk Veterinärtidskrift, 1946. (Box 1)
  - Egan, James A. "Facts and fallacies concerning interstate reciprocity in medical licenses." A paper read by invitation, before the Illinois State Medical Society at Springfield, 17 May 1906. (Box 1)
  - Ernest, L.B. and Elmer Lash. "Tuberculin testing of livestock." United States Department of Agriculture, Circular, No. 249, December 1922. (Box 1)
  - Ernst, Harold C. "Progress of Medicine." An oration delivered before the Norfolf District Medical Socity at the Celebratin of the Semi-Centennial of its organization, 8 May 1900. (Box 1)
  - Evans, Alice C. "Studies on brucella (alkaligenes) melitensis." Treasury Department United States Public Health Service, Hygenic Laboratory Bulletin, August 1925. (Box 1)
  - Evans, Walter H. "Copper sulphate and germination: treatment of seed with copper sulphate to prevent the attacks of fungi." U.S. Department of Agriculture Division of Vegetable and Physiology and Pathology, Bulletin No. 10, 1896. (Box 1)
  - Exelby, Paul A. "An analysis of the results of treatment of cases of type II arthritis in the Stanford clinic." Reprinted from the Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, September 1930. (Box 1)
- F
  - Fairchild, D.G. "Bodeaux Mixture as fungicide." U.S. Department of Agriculture Division of Vegetable Pathology, 1894. (Box 1)
  - ______. "Experiments in preventing leaf diseases of nursery stock in Western New York." Reprinted form the Journal of Mycology, 1891. (Box 1)
  - Farrand, Livingston. "Health demonstrations in the United States." Reprinted from the American Journal of Public Health, February 1927. (Box 1)
  - Field, George W. "Notes on the mortality of incubator chicks." Agricultural Experiment Station of the Rhode Island College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts, Bulletin No. 61, December 1899. (Box 1)
  - Fincher, M.G. and W.L. Williams. "Arrested development of the muellerian ducts associated with inbreeding." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1926. (Box 1)
  - Finlay, Carlos Jr. "President's Address." Presented before the American Public Health Association, Havana, Cuba, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Fischer, Paul. "Bovine tuberculosis." Experiment Station of the Kansas State Agricultural College, Bulletin No. 79, April 1898. (Box 1)
  - Fish, J.C.L. "Typhoid fever epidemic at Palo Alto, California." A Report made to the Palo Alto Board of Health, 1905. (Box 1)
  - Fish, Pierre A."An acid-proof table top." Reprinted from the Journal of Applied Microscopy and Laboratory Methods, Vol. VI, No.3. (Box 1)
  - ________. "The action of strong currents of electricity upon nerve cells." Reprinted from the proceedings of the American Microscopical Society, Vol. XVII, 1895. (Box 1)
  - ________. "The anatomy of the fur seal: The brain." Extracted from The Fur Seals and Fur Seal Islands of the North Pacific Ocean, Part III, 1899. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Black tops for laboratory tables." Reprinted from The Anatomical Record, March 1911. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Blood phosphates in milk fever." Reprinted from the proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1929. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Bob veal and the conservation of the meat supply." Reprinted from the proceedings of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 1912. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Bob veal and the public." Reprinted from America Veterinary Review, May 1912. (Box 1)
  - ________. "The brain of the fur seal." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology Vol. VIII, Nos. 1 and 2, 1898. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Brain preservation with a resume of some old and new methods." Reprinted from the Wilder Quarter-Century Book, 1893. (Box 1)
  - ________. "A brief veterinary survey." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian Vol. XX, No.2, April 1930. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Castration, nutrition and growth." From the proceedings of the Third Pan-American Scientific Congress, held at Lima, Peru, December 1924. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The central nervous system of desmognathus fusca." Reprinted from the Journal of Morphology, 1895. (Box 2)
  - ________. " The cerebral fissures of the atlantic walrus." Reprinted from the proceedings of the United States National Museum, Vol. XXVI, 1903. (Box 2)
  - ________. " A combined locker and laboratory table." Reprinted from the Journal of Applied Microscopy and Laboratory Methods, Vol.VI, No.3. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The comparative fat content of the portal vein as determined by the presence of fat particles with the darkfield microscope." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1922. (Box 2)
  - ________ and Charles E. Hayden. "A comparison of the blood of a normal and two castrated billy goats." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1926. (Box 2)
  - ________. "A comparison of the brain of the fur seal (callorhinus ursinus) with the brains of some other carnivora." Reprinted from the proceedings of the Association of American Anatomists, December 1897. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The digestibility and decomposability of bob veal." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College for the years 1912-1913. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The endocrine system and growth." Reprinted from The Cornell Veterinarian, April 1925. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The epithelium of the brain cavities." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Society of Microscopists, 1890. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The exchange of air in the eustachian or guttural pouches of the horse." Reprinted from the American Journal of Physiology, May 1910. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The form and relations of the nerve cells and fibers in desmognathus fusca." Reprinted from Anatomischer Anzeiger, ca. 1894. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Formalin for the preservation of brains." Journal of Comparative Neurology, July 1895. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Further observations on bob veal." New York State Veterinary College, Ithaca, N.Y., 1912. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The identification of animals by branding and otherwise." Circular No.2, New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University, 1910. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The indusium of the callosum." Reprinted from the Journal of Comparative Neurology, June 1893. (Box 2)
  - ________. "James Law." Reprinted from Cornell Veterinarian, July 1921. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Milk fever." The Proceedings of the Eleventh International Veterinary Congress, 1930. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Morbidity and mortality in army animals." Reprinted from The Cornell Veterinarian, April 1920. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The mummification of small anatomical and zoological specimens." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Association of American Anatomists, December 1897. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The nerve cell as a unit." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, Vol. VIII, Nos. 1 and 2, 1898. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Neutral red in histology and bacteriology." N.Y. State Veterinary College, Ithaca, N.Y. (Box 2)
  - ________. "A new clearer for collodinized objects." Proceedings of the American Microscopial Society, 1893. (Box 2)
  - ________. "A note on the cerebral fissuration of the seal." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, March 1896. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Notes on technique." Reprinted from the Transactions of the American Microscopical Society, 1896. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Nutrition Trails." Reprinted from the Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, June 1924. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Observations on the veterinary schools in Europe." Reprinted from the proceedings of the 44th Annual Meeting of the American Veterinary Medical Association, September 1907. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Outlines of lectures on invertebrate zoology." Cornell publication, n.d. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Physiologic Relations - Poultry." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University, 1914-1915. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Physiology as a fundamental in veterinary education." Reprinted from Science, November 1911. (Box 2)